<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pablo Barajas</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pablo Barajas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Rules for life</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-060-19-12rulesforlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-060-19-12rulesforlife/</guid>
      <description>Following Jordan Peterson 12 rules for life, I want to write my own. Keeping in mind that these can and will probably change over time which can sound contradictory because rules should not change, but I understand my limitations and understand that people change points of view. So here it goes:
  Assume your temperament will always be somewhat childish and impatient, and set your rules accordingly, knowing that you cannot abide by rules for rules sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Tutorial</title>
      <link>/posts/website-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/website-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>As part of a workshop hosted by the Orange County R User Group (OCRUG) and Merage Analytics Club (MAC), I gave this presentation: Link to the slides here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Books</title>
      <link>/blog/free-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/free-books/</guid>
      <description>The Open Source community is amazing, they do great work and share it freely with the world. I have compiled a list of free books and will continue to update it as I find more.
 R for Data Science Efficient R programming [Creating Websites with R Markdown] (https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/) R Markdown: The Definitive Guide Text Mining with R Happy Git and GitHub for the useR Modern Data Science with R [The Unix Workbench] (https://seankross.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simpsons by Gil Henriques</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-10-26-simpsons_by_gilhenriques/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 21:14:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-10-26-simpsons_by_gilhenriques/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse)library(showtext) # for google fontsfont_add_google(&amp;quot;Gaegu&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;gaegu&amp;quot;)showtext_auto()# Read and prepare data ---------------------------------------------------df &amp;lt;- read_delim(&amp;quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/rfordatascience/tidytuesday/master/data/2019/2019-08-27/simpsons-guests.csv&amp;quot;, delim = &amp;quot;|&amp;quot;, quote = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;)df2 &amp;lt;- df %&amp;gt;% mutate(number = strsplit(as.character(number), &amp;quot;; &amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;% unnest() %&amp;gt;% # Splits rows that contain multiple episodes into multiple rowsgroup_by(season) %&amp;gt;% summarize(guests_per_episode = n_distinct(guest_star)/n_distinct(number))# Prepare for plot --------------------------------------------------------# I want the axes and the line connecting the points to look hand-drawn, so I will use geom_line + jitter to draw themspline_int &amp;lt;- as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hans Rosling - Bubble Chart</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-10-26-hans_rosling_bubble_chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-10-26-hans_rosling_bubble_chart/</guid>
      <description>When I was in college taking my first Statistics class our proffesor showed us the Hans Rosling Ted Talk and I was fascinated by it. Here is the code to recreate part of that talk.
  We can do it in R.Code by Keith Mcnulty
# libraries neededlibrary(tidyverse)library(ggplot2)library(viridis)library(gganimate)library(wbstats)# pull the country data down from the World Bank - three indicatorswbstats::wb(indicator = c(&amp;quot;SP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kidney Stones and Simpson&#39;s Paradox</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-06-29-kidney_stones_simpsons_paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-06-29-kidney_stones_simpsons_paradox/</guid>
      <description>1. A new look at an old research studyIn 1986, a group of urologists in London published a research paper in The British Medical Journal that compared the effectiveness of two different methods to remove kidney stones. Treatment A was open surgery (invasive), and treatment B was percutaneous nephrolithotomy (less invasive). When they looked at the results from 700 patients, treatment B had a higher success rate. However, when they only looked at the subgroup of patients different kidney stone sizes, treatment A had a better success rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Bias in Graduate Admissions</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-05-29-genderbias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-05-29-genderbias/</guid>
      <description>BerkeleyIn 1973, The University of California - Berkeley was one of the top-ranked universities in the United States. As such Berkeley attracted thousands of applicants to its graduate school. But how many made the cut?
We will start off by loading the UCBAdmissions dataset, which is included in base R. This shows the number of students male and female who were admitted or rejected from the six largest departments at Berkeley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Inequalities in Life Expectancy</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-04-29-visualizing_inequalities_in_lifeexpectancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-04-29-visualizing_inequalities_in_lifeexpectancy/</guid>
      <description>United Nations life expectancy dataLife expectancy at birth is a measure of the average a living being is expected to live. It takes into account several demographic factors like gender, country, or year of birth.
Life expectancy at birth can vary along time or between countries because of many causes: the evolution of medicine, the degree of development of countries, or the effect of armed conflicts. Life expectancy varies between gender, as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tableau</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-22-tableau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-22-tableau/</guid>
      <description>You can find a public dashboard I created here Tableau Public Profile</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-19-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-19-quotes/</guid>
      <description>I will be updating this page with my favorite quotes &amp;ldquo;When the facts change, I change my opinion. What do you do, sir?&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; ― John Maynard Keynes
“It’s not what you preach, it’s what you tolerate.” ― Jocko Willink
“Don’t expect to be motivated every day to get out there and make things happen. You won’t be. Don’t count on motivation. Count on Discipline.” ― Jocko Willink
“Care about what other people think and you will always be their prisoner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>