<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Pablo Barajas</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Pablo Barajas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Rules for life</title>
      <link>/blog/2020-060-19-12rulesforlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020-060-19-12rulesforlife/</guid>
      <description>Following Jordan Peterson 12 rules for life, I want to write my own. Keeping in mind that these can and will probably change over time which can sound contradictory because rules should not change, but I understand my limitations and understand that people change points of view. So here it goes:
  Assume your temperament will always be somewhat childish and impatient, and set your rules accordingly, knowing that you cannot abide by rules for rules sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Books</title>
      <link>/blog/free-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/free-books/</guid>
      <description>The Open Source community is amazing, they do great work and share it freely with the world. I have compiled a list of free books and will continue to update it as I find more.
 R for Data Science Efficient R programming [Creating Websites with R Markdown] (https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/) R Markdown: The Definitive Guide Text Mining with R Happy Git and GitHub for the useR Modern Data Science with R [The Unix Workbench] (https://seankross.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tableau</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-22-tableau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-22-tableau/</guid>
      <description>You can find a public dashboard I created here Tableau Public Profile</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-19-quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-19-quotes/</guid>
      <description>I will be updating this page with my favorite quotes &amp;ldquo;When the facts change, I change my opinion. What do you do, sir?&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; ― John Maynard Keynes
“It’s not what you preach, it’s what you tolerate.” ― Jocko Willink
“Don’t expect to be motivated every day to get out there and make things happen. You won’t be. Don’t count on motivation. Count on Discipline.” ― Jocko Willink
“Care about what other people think and you will always be their prisoner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-04-19-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-04-19-markdown/</guid>
      <description>Inline styles：
strong, emphasis, strong and emphasis,code, underline, strikethrough, 😂🤣, Link
Headings:
Heading 1 Heading 2 Heading 3 Heading 4 Heading 5 Heading 6 Here&amp;rsquo;s some basic text.
And here&amp;rsquo;s some italics
Here&amp;rsquo;s some bold text.
What about a link?
Here&amp;rsquo;s a bulleted list:
 First item   Second item   Third item  Here&amp;rsquo;s a numbered list:
 First Second Third  Here&amp;rsquo;s an unordered list:
 Unordered list item 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>